AUGUSTINE ODUOR

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 254 703394791, augustineodu9@gmail.com

PROFILE

Passionate software developer with a background in object-oriented programming, writing testing, debugging code, and creating user interfaces. Proficient also in multiple programming languages and frameworks. Excellent at grasping new technologies quickly; competent in both team and self-directed settings. An expert in cutting-edge development methodologies, tools, and processes that are useful for designing and rolling out software applications

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2021-11- ICT Graduate Trainee

2022-11 Uwezo Fund, Nairobi

Duties and Responsibilities

- Installing or ensuring the installation of cables, operating systems, or suitable software, and setting up equipment for employee use
- ICT asset management responsible for the inventory and track all electronic-assets
- Network support and troubleshooting In response to users' recognized issues, provide support for business systems, networks, and the Internet.
- Preventive maintenance of ICT equipment-Create, organize and maintain a log of issues and solutions with other technical support analysts.
- Network installation and configuration resolving network issues
- Troubleshooting reported device-related faults Communicate electronically and in person with computer users who are having issues identifying and recording issues
- Writing reports and minutes of events and meetings
- Writing reports and minutes of events and meetings
- Installing or ensuring the installation of cables, operating systems, or suitable software, and setting up equipment for employee use

2021-05- Software Developer Trainee

2021-08 DewCis Solutions, Nairobi

Duties and Responsibilities

- Developing sites and applications using scrum methodologies
- Development of websites in the development department under code Pamoja school.
- Blogging on sites under Sacco, welfare, and chama departments.
- Using open Baraza frameworks to develop applications using Java language.
- Reviewing of systems software in Chama, welfare and Sacco departments
- Solving Java problems and developing applications.

EDUCATION

2016-09- Bachelor of Science: Mathematics with Computing

2020-12 Kisii University - Kisii

Graduated with Second Class Honors (Upper Division) in Mathematics and Computing

2012-02- Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

2015-11 Ambira High School - Siaya

Scored an average of B+ in Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (K.C.S.E).

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, C++, JavaScript, PHP, C#
- Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), React, Node.js
- Database Management: MySQL, MongoDB, MariaDB, PostgreSQL
- Frameworks and Libraries: Django Python, Spring Boot Java
- API Development Familiarity with frameworks like Django Rest Framework, Express.js, and Spring Boot
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Software Development Lifecycle: Agile, Scrum
- Problem-Solving
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Effective Communication.
- Teamwork and collaboration
- · Adaptable and flexible
- Please feel free to explore my GitHub page at [GitHub URL] to gain a deeper understanding of
 my projects, access detailed documentation, and review the source code and commit history.

CAREER OBJECTIVES

- Continuously improve technical skills and stay up-to-date with the latest software development technologies, languages, frameworks, and best practices.
- Foster effective collaboration with cross-functional teams, to ensure smooth project execution and successful outcomes.
- Strive for writing clean, maintainable, and well-documented code, adhering to coding standards and best practices. Emphasize code reuse, modularity, and scalability.
- Understand end-user needs and design software with a focus on usability, accessibility, and a positive user experience.